Call me on: +46736807235

Send me a note at: andre.kaplan@gmail.com

Check out my LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andrekaplan

Mail me a letter: Fredrikslundsgatan 4 58939 Linköping Sweden



Resume André Kaplan

Profile

I'm a usability-obsessed tech geek who's into creative photography, great design, sustainability, space exploration and mind expanding experiences.

I believe in the concept that the user is central in every step and that a service should be designed according to the possibilities and limitations presented by its users.

You can usually find me optimising a workflow, designing an interface or just taping two things together.

Experience

UX DESIGNER FOR THE NEXT GENERATION GRIPEN, SAAB AB, LINKÖPING, 2016-

My current occupation is as part of the conceptual design team where we design the human machine interaction in the next generation Gripen aircraft. We use an iterative design and prototyping loop with focus on user testing to create interactions that are intuitive, consistent and reliable is high stress situations.

HMI SYSTEM DEVELOPER FOR GRIPEN C/D SUPPORT SYSTEMS, SAAB AB, LINKÖPING, 2014-2015
I spent a year being responsible for the UX of the Mission Support System used with the Gripen aircraft. The work included design, development, testing, manuals, educational material and also holding courses for users. I worked in an interdisciplinary team using agile development methods.

HMI SYSTEM DEVELOPER FOR GRIPEN C/D FIGHTER JET, SAAB AB, LINKÖPING, 2011-2014

I started my career at Saab in an agile development team with duties covering everything from design to programming and extensively testing the finished solution. Work was conducted with other teams creating the backend while our team focused mainly on the interaction with the user. This required interdisciplinary cross-team communication and collaboration and led to many interesting exchanges of ideas and experiences.

CONSULTANT, DFIND, LINKÖPING, 2011

Were onsite as a First Line Support Agent at CSC. Worked with solving IT-related issues for clients over telephone and email.

Call me on:

+46736807235 andre.kaplan@gmail.com

Send me a note at:

Check out my LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andrekaplan

Mail me a letter: Fredrikslundsgatan 4 58939 Linköping Sweden

Education

Linköping University - Cognitive Science, 2007-2010

Bachelor thesis available at LiU University Press: "Att designa ett multiplattformsystem: Interaktionsdesign möter agila projektmetoder."

This thesis examines the multiplatform design issues of a development project using agile project methods and how they were resolved. Data was gathered through observation, photography and keeping of a journal using action research as a methodological framework. The thesis is concluded with recommendations on how to deal with these issues in similar projects under similar conditions.

Skills

Primary skills and experience revolve around user research in different forms, prototyping, agile methodology, UI design, systems design and documentation, Human Factors.

Fast learner of different computer programs and systems, basic skills in programming (C++, Python etc.), systems testing, team leading.

References

Available by demand.